Finding Aid for the Collection of Underground, Alternative and Extremist Literature LSC.0050
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Organization Materials
  - N
    - National Action Launched Against Relaxed Morals, Incorporated. Short Hills, New Jersey. (Box 123)
    - National Alliance Against Racism and Political Repression. New York, New York. (Box 123)
    - National Alliance of Russian Solidarists, n.p. (Box 123)
    - National American Bulletin. New York, New York. (Box 123)
    - National Americanism Commission Sub-Committee on Subversive Activites, the American Legion., n.p. (Box 123)
    - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, n.p. (Box 123)
    - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, n.p. (Box 124)
    - National Blue Star Mothers of America. Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. (Box 123)
    - National Catholic Conference for Interracial Justice. Chicago, Illinois. (Box 123)
    - National Citizens Commission for the Public Schools. New York, New York. (Box 123)
    - National Citizens Committee for Broadcasting. New York, New York. (Box 123)
    - National Citizens Political Action Committee. New York, New York. (Box 123)
    - National Citizens' Committee to Defend Academic Freedom at St. John's University. New York, New York. (Box 123)
    - National Civil Liberties Clearing House. Washington, D.C. (Box 123)
    - National Coalition Against the Death Penalty. Washington, D.C. (Box 123)
    - National Coalition to Ban Handguns. Washington, D.C. (Box 123)
    - National Commission on Resources for Youth. New York, New York. (Box 123)
    - National Committee Against Censorship of the Theatre Arts. New York, New York. (Box 123)
    - National Committee Against Discrimination in Housing. New York, New York. (Box 123)
    - National Committee Against Repressive Legislation. Washington, D.C. (Box 123)
    - National Committee for a Fair Minimum Wage. Washington, D.C. (Box 123)
    - National Committee for a Free Europe, Incorporated. New York, New York. (Box 123)
    - National Committee for a Sane Nuclear Policy, n.p. (Box 125)
    - National Committee for a Tribute to Congressional Liberals, n.p. (Box 125)
    - National Committee for Action. Washington, D.C. (Box 125)
    - National Committee for an Effective Congress. New York, New York. (Box 125)
    - National Committee for Economic Freedom. Los Angeles, California. (Box 125)
    - National Committee for Free Europe, Incorporated, n.p. (Box 125)
    - National Committee for People's Rights. New York, New York. (Box 125)
    - National Committee for the Defence of Children. London, England. (Box 125)
    - National Committee for the Defense of Political Prisoners. New York, New York. (Box 125)
    - National Committee of Americans of Polish Descent. New York, New York. (Box 125)
    - National Committee of Protestant Associates, n.p. (Box 125)
    - National Committee on Atomic Information. Washington, D.C. (Box 125)
    - National Committee on Tithing in Investment. Washington, D.C. (Box 125)
    - National Committee to Aid Victims of German Fascism. New York, New York. (Box 125)
    - National Committee to Combat Anti-semitism. New York, New York. (Box 126)
    - National Committee to Secure Justice in the Rosenberg Case. New York, New York. (Box 126)
    - National Committee to Uphold Constitutional Government. New York, New York. (Box 126)
    - National Committee to Win the Peace. Washington, D.C. (Box 126)
    - National Committee Unemployed Councils. New York, New York. (Box 126)
    - National Conference for New Politics. New York, New York. (Box 126)
    - National Conference of Christians and Jews, Incorporated, n.p. (Box 126)
    - National Conference of Citizens for Religious Freedom, n.p. (Box 126)
    - National Confernce on Soviet Jewry. New York, New York. (Box 126)
    - National Cooperatives, Incorporated. New York, New York. (Box 126)
    - National Cooperheads. Los Angeles, California. (Box 126)
    - National Coordinating Committee for Justice Under Law. Van Nuys, California. (Box 126)
    - National Coordinating Committee to End the War in Vietnam, n.p. (Box 126)
    - National Council Against Conscription. Washington, D.C. (Box 126)
    - National Council for American Education. New York, New York. (Box 126)
    - National Council for Prevention of War. Washington, D.C. (Box 126)
    - National Council for Reduction of Armanments. Washington, D.C. (Box 126)
    - National Council of American Soviet Friendship. New York, New York. (Box 126)
    - National Council of Arts, Sciences, and Professions. Southern California Chapter. Hollywood, California. (Box 127)
    - National Council of Churches, n.p. (Box 127)
    - National Council of Jewish Women. New York, New York. (Box 127)
    - National Council of Labour. London, England. (Box 127)
    - National Council of Negro Women, Incorporated. New York, New York. (Box 127)
    - National Council of the Arts, Sciences and Professions. New York, New York. (Box 127)
    - National Council on Crime and Delinquency, n.p. (Box 127)
    - National Council to Control Handguns. Washington, D.C. (Box 127)
    - National Council to Repeal the Draft. Washington, D.C. (Box 127)
    - National Defense Committee. New York, New York. (Box 127)
    - National Economic Council, Incorporated. New York, New York. (Box 127)
    - National Education Program. Searcy, Arkansas. (Box 127)
    - National Epic League, Incorporated. Inglewood, California. (Box 127)
    - National Falcon Office. Chicago, Illinois. (Box 127)
    - National Farm Workers Ministry. Los Angeles, California. (Box 127)
    - National Farmers Union. Denver, Colorado. (Box 127)
    - National Federation for Constitutional Liberties. Washington, D.C. (Box 127)
    - National Guardian. New York, New York. (Box 5,6,127)
    - National Health Federation, Monrovia, California. (Box 127)
    - National Health Insurance - U.S., n.p. (Box 127)
    - National Jewish Welfare Board, n.p. (Box 127)
    - National Joint Action Committee for Genuine Social Insurance, New York. (Box 127)
    - National Lawyers Guild. Los Angeles, California. (Box 127)
    - National League of Senior Citizens. Los Angeles, California. (Box 127)
    - National League of Women Voters. Washington, D.C. (Box 127)
    - National Liberal League, Incorporated. New York, New York. (Box 127)
    - National Manpower Council, n.p. (Box 127)
    - National Negro Congress. New York, New York. (Box 127)
    - National Negro Labor Council, n.p. (Box 127)
    - National Organization for Women. Washington, D.C. (Box 128)
    - National Pacifist Youth Conference, n.p. (Box 128)
    - National Party, U.S.A. Los Angeles, California. (Box 128)
    - National Pension Advocate. Los Angeles, California. (Box 128)
    - National Planning Association, n.p. (Box 128)
    - National Police Gazette, n.p. (Box 128)
    - National Political Action Committee, C.I.O. New York, New York. (Box 128)
    - National Precinct Workers, Incorporated. Chicago, Illinois. (Box 128)
    - National Pure Water Committee. Los Angeles, California. (Box 128)
    - National Putnam Letters Committee. Washington, D.C. (Box 128)
    - National Religion and Labor Foundation, New Haven, Connecticut. (Box 128)
    - National Renaissance Bulletin. New York, New York. (Box 128)
      Note: 1950(?)-1956.
    - National Renaissance Party. New York, New York. (Box 128)
    - National Republic Publishing Company. Washington, D.C. (Box 129)
    - National Review. New York, New York. (Box 129)
    - National Rifle Association. Washington, D.C. (Box 129)
    - National Right to Work Committee. Washington, D.C. (Box 129)
    - National Rip-Saw Publishing Company. St. Louis, Missouri. (Box 129)
    - National Security League. New York, New York. (Box 129)
    - National Service Board for Religious Objectors. Washington, D.C. (Box 129)
    - National Sharecroppers Fund. New York, New York. (Box 129)
    - National Short Ballot Organization. New York, New York. (Box 129)
    - National Socialist White People's Party. Los Angeles, California. (Box 129)
    - National Socialist White People's Party. Arlington, Virginia. (Box 129)
    - National Society for the Promotion of Industrial Education, n.p. (Box 129)
    - National States Rights Party. Birmingham, Alabama. (Box 129)
    - National Student League, n.p. (Box 129)
    - National Student Union, n.p. (Box 129)
    - National Unemployed Workers' Movement. London, England. (Box 129)
    - National Union of Public Employees. London, England. (Box 129)
    - National United Committee to Free Angela Davis. Los Angeles, California. (Box 129)
    - National Urban League. New York, New York. (Box 129)
    - National White Americans Party. Birmingham, Alabama. (Box 129)
    - National Women's Health Network. Washington, D.C. (Box 129)
    - National Women's Political Caucus. Washington, D.C. (Box 136)
    - National Youth Alliance. Washington, D.C. (Box 136)
    - Native American Rights Fund. Boulder, Colorado. (Box 136)
    - Necessities of Life Enterprises. Sacramento, California. (Box 136)
    - Negative Population Growth, Incorporated. New York, New York. (Box 136)
    - Negotiation Now. New York, New York. (Box 136)
    - Negro Committee to Aid Spain. New York, New York. (Box 136)
    - Negroes - U.S., n.p. (Box 130)
    - Negroes and The Law, n.p. (Box 130)
    - Negroes and White Sumpremacy, n.p. (Box 131)
    - Neighborhood Action Group. Los Angeles, California. (Box 131)
    - Network of Patriotic Letter Writers. Pasadena, California. (Box 131)
    - New Age Awareness Foundation, Incorporated. Los Angeles, California. (Box 131)
    - New Age Publishers. New York, New York. (Box 131)
    - New American Movement, n.p. (Box 131)
    - New Century Foundation, n.p. (Box 131)
    - New Century Publishers. New York, New York. (Box 136)
    - New Challenge. New York, New York. (Box 131)
    - New Cosmic Star. Lawndale, California. (Box 131)
    - New Deal on Taxes. Los Angeles, California. (Box 131)
    - New Directions. Washington, D.C. (Box 131)
    - New England Anti-Vivesection Society, n.p. (Box 131)
    - New England Rally for God and Country. Dedham, Massachusetts. (Box 131)
    - New Hungary. Washington, D.C. (Box 131)
    - New International. New York, New York. (Box 131)
    - New Jewish Agenda. Los Angeles, California. (Box 131)
    - New Left School of Los Angeles. Los Angeles, California. (Box 131)
    - New Masses. New York, New York. (Box 131)
    - New Outlook. New York, New York. (Box 133)
    - New Party News. Trenton, North Dakota. (Box 133)
    - New Times. Moscow, Russia. (Box 133)
    - New Workers School. New York, New York. (Box 133)
    - New World Review. New York, New York. (Box 133)
    - New York Free Trade Club, n.p. (Box 133)
    - New York Labor News Company. New York, New York. (Box 133)
    - New York State Socialist Party. New York, New York. (Box 133)
    - New York Workers Book Shop, n.p. (Box 134)
    - News & Letters. The Root of Mankind is Man. Detroit, Michigan. (Box 134)
      Note: April 1965.
    - Newton-Cleaver Defense Committee. Los Angeles, California. (Box 134)
    - No Death Toys Newsletter. Los Angeles, California. (Box 134)
    - No More War Publication Committee. New York, New York. (Box 134)
    - Noble News. Los Angeles, California. (Box 134)
    - Non-Partisan Labor Defense. San Francisco, California. (Box 134)
    - Non-Sectarian Anti-Nazi League to Champion Human Rights, Incorporated, New York. (Box 134)
    - Non-violent Action Committee. Los Angeles, California. (Box 134)
    - North American Committee to Aid Spanish Democracy. New York, New York. (Box 134)
    - Northeast Peace Center. Los Angeles, California. (Box 134)
    - Now. Los Angeles, California. (Box 134)
    - Nuclear Proliferation, n.p. (Box 134)
    - Nutrition, n.p. (Box 134)
  - O
    - Obscenity (Law), n.p. (Box 135)
    - Office of the Americas. Santa Monica, California. (Box 135)
    - Oil, n.p. (Box 135)
    - Oklahoma Committee to Defend Political Prisoners. Oklahoma City, Oklahoma. (Box 135)
    - Old Age Pension Protective League, n.p. (Box 135)
    - One Big Union Club. New York, New York. (Box 135)
    - One Million Americans. Long Beach, California. (Box 135)
    - Open Campus. San Francisco, California. (Box 135)
    - Operation Freedom. Cincinnati, Ohio. (Box 135)
    - Opposition West. Stanford, California. (Box 135)
    - Organizational Research Associates. Garden Grove, California. (Box 135)
    - Ortiz, Ricardo Chavez, n.p. (Box 135)
    - Osaka Mainichi Publishing Company. Osaka, Japan. (Box 135)
    - Ottawa Committee to End the War in Vietnam. Ottowa, Onatario, Canada. (Box 135)
    - Our Times, n.p. (Box 135)
  - P
    - Pacific Associates. Carmel, California. (Box 135)
    - Pacific Publishing Foundation. San Francisco, California. (Box 135)
    - Pacific Southwest Institute of Religious Liberals. Los Angeles, California. (Box 135)
    - Pacific Studies Center. East Palo Alto, California. (Box 135)
    - Pacifism, n.p. (Box 135)
    - Pacifist Research Bureau. Ithaca, New York. (Box 135)
    - Palo Alto Peace Club. Palo Alto, California. (Box 135)
    - Pan American Development Foundation. Washington, D.C. (Box 135)
    - Paper Tiger. Boston, Massachusetts. (Box 135)
    - Parents Educational Study Committee Incorporated. Torrance, California. (Box 136)
    - Parliament of Man, n.p. (Box 136)
    - Pasadena Committee to Legalize Abortion. Pasadena, California. (Box 136)
    - Pathfinder Fund. Boston, Massachusetts. (Box 136)
    - Patrick Henry Club. Los Angeles, California. (Box 136)
    - Patriotic Foundation for Americanism. Santa Monica, California. (Box 136)
    - Patriotic Tract Society. St. Louis, Missouri. (Box 136)
    - Paulist Press. New York, New York. (Box 136)
    - Pax, n.p. (Box 136)
    - Peace, n.p. (Box 136, Box 137)
    - Peace Action Council. Los Angeles, California. (Box 138)
    - Peace and Freedom Party, n.p. (Box 138)
    - Peace Assembly of the City Council of Youth. Cleveland, Ohio. (Box 138)
    - Peace Education Clearing House. La Habra, California. (Box 138)
    - Peace Happenings. Inglewood, California. (Box 138)
    - Peacemaker Movement. Cincinnati, Ohio. (Box 138)
    - Pension Plans, n.p. (Box 138)
    - Pentagon Papers Peace Project. Los Angeles, California. (Box 138)
    - People for the American Way. Marion, Ohio. (Box 138)
    - People's Institute. San Francisco, California. (Box 138)
    - People's League for Abundance. New York, New York. (Box 138)
    - People's Lobby, Incorporated. Washington, D.C. (Box 138)
    - People's Party, n.p. (Box 138)
    - People's Peace. Los Angeles, California. (Box 138)
    - People's Russian Information Bureau. London, England. (Box 138)
    - People's Voice. Los Angeles, California. (Box 138)
    - People's World. San Francisco, California. (Box 138)
    - Peoples Educational Center. Hollywood, California. (Box 138)
    - Peoples Forum Publishing Company. New York, New York. (Box 138)
    - Personal Rights Association. Shropshire, England. (Box 139)
    - Petal Paper. Montgomery, Alabama. (Box 139)
    - Philadelphia Yearly Meeting of Friends. Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. (Box 139)
    - Philip L. Allen Defense Committee of the Unitarian Church. Los Angeles, California. (Box 139)
    - Phyllis Schlafly Report. Alton, Illinois. (Box 139)
    - Physicians for Social Responsibility. Cambridge, Massachusetts. (Box 139)
    - Physicians Forum for the Study of Medical Care. New York, New York. (Box 139)
    - Pine Tree Publications. Santa Ana, California. (Box 139)
    - Pioneer Publishers. New York, New York. (Box 139)
    - Planned Communities, Incorporated. New York, New York. (Box 140)
    - Planned Parenthood - World Population. New York, New York. (Box 140)
    - Planned Parenthood - World Population. Los Angeles, California. (Box 140)
    - Planning and Conservation League. Sacramento, California. (Box 140)
    - Platform. Los Angeles, California. (Box 140)
    - Plough Publishing House, Rifton. New York, New York. (Box 140)
    - Plumb Plan League. Washington, D.C. (Box 140)
    - POEE. San Francisco, California. (Box 136)
    - Poland - Politics and Government, n.p. (Box 140)
    - Polemic Publishers. Los Angeles, California. (Box 140)
    - Police Cruelty, n.p. (Box 140)
    - Polish Information Center, n.p. (Box 140)
    - Political Asylum, n.p. (Box 140)
    - Political Rights Defense Fund. Los Angeles, California. (Box 140)
    - Political Science Pocket Library. New York, New York. (Box 140)
    - Politics. New York, New York. (Box 140)
    - Politics - Controversial, n.p. (Box 140)
    - Population Institute. Washington, D.C. (Box 140)
    - Port Chicago Vigil. Port Chicago, California. (Box 140)
    - Portugese - American Committee on Foreign Affairs. Boston, Massachusetts. (Box 140)
    - Post War World Council. New York, New York. (Box 140)
    - Postal Litho Printing Service. Whittier, California. (Box 140)
    - Postwar Information Exchange, Incorporated. New York, New York. (Box 140)
    - Poverty, n.p. (Box 141)
    - Pressworthly Publications Corporation. Los Angeles, California. (Box 141)
    - Prison Reform, n.p. (Box 141)
    - Prisoners of War, n.p. (Box 141)
    - Private Enterprise, n.p. (Box 141)
    - Probe. Boston, Massachusetts. (Box 141)
    - Professional Educators Defense Fund, Sherman Oaks, California. (Box 141)
    - Professional Group. Los Angeles, California. (Box 141)
    - Profit and Progress. Los Angeles, California. (Box 141)
    - Progressive. Madison, Wisconsin. (Box 141)
    - Progressive Book Shop. Los Angeles, California. (Box 141)
    - Progressive Citizens of America, n.p. (Box 141)
    - Progressive Labor Movement. Brooklyn, New York. (Box 141)
    - Progressive Labor Party, n.p. (Box 141)
    - Progressive Party, n.p. (Box 141)
    - Proletarian Party of America. Chicago, Illinois. (Box 141)
    - Promoting Enduring Peace, Incorporated. Woodmont, Connecticut. (Box 141)
    - Propaganda, n.p. (Box 141)
    - Propaganda, German, n.p. (Box 141)
    - Protestants & Other American United. Washington, D.C. (Box 142)
    - Provisional Committee for Cuba. New York, New York. (Box 142)
    - Psychology, n.p. (Box 142)
    - Public Affairs Committee, Incorporated, n.p. (Box 142)
    - Public Affairs Press. Washington, D.C. (Box 142)
    - Public Citizen, Incorporated. Washington, D.C. (Box 142)
    - Public Information Center. Washington, D.C. (Box 142)
    - Public Service Research Council. Vienna, Virginia. (Box 142)
  - R
    - Race Problems, n.p. (Box 142)
    - Race Relations Information Center. Nashville, Tennessee. (Box 142)
    - Racism - U.S., n.p. (Box 142)
    - Radical Education Project. Ann Arbor, Michigan. (Box 142)
    - Radio Liberty. New York, New York. (Box 142)
    - Radio Stations, n.p. (Box 142)
    - Ramparts. Menlo Park, California. (Box 142)
    - Rand School of Social Science. New York, New York. (Box 143)
    - Rand School Press. New York, New York. (Box 143)
    - Rationalism, n.p. (Box 144)
    - Rationalist. Melbourne, Australia. (Box 144)
    - Reactionary. Los Angeles, California. (Box 144)
    - Reciprocal Disarmament. Healdsburg, California. (Box 144)
    - Red Falcons of America, n.p. (Box 144)
    - Relief Committee for Victims of Fascism. London, England. (Box 144)
    - Religion - Controversial Literature, n.p. (Box 144, Box 145)
    - Religious Coalition for Abortion Rights. Washington, D.C. (Box 145)
    - Religious Freedom Committee. New York, New York. (Box 145)
    - Reminder of Our National Heritage, n.p. (Box 145)
    - Reporter for Conscience' Sake. Washington, D.C. (Box 145)
    - Republic. Journal of Fact and Opinion. Manhattan Beach, California. (Box 146)
    - Republican National Committee. Washington, D.C. (Box 146)
    - Resistance. Los Angeles, California. (Box 146)
    - Retirement Life Payments Association, n.p. (Box 146)
    - Review. New York, New York. (Box 146)
    - Review of the News. Belmont, Massachusetts. (Box 146)
    - Revisionism, n.p. (Box 146)
    - Revolutionary Communist Party (British Section of the 4th International). London, England. (Box 146)
    - Revolutionary People's Constitutional Convention. Los Angeles, California. (Box 146)
    - Revolutionary Union. Los Angeles, California. (Box 146)
    - Riggs' Free Health Act. Los Angeles, California. (Box 146)
    - Right. San Francisco, California. (Box 146)
    - Right Cause Publishing Company. Chicago, Illinois. (Box 146)
    - Right of Assembly and Movement Committee. Los Angeles, California. (Box 146)
    - Road to Freedom Group. Boston, Massachusetts. (Box 146)
    - Rural Advancement Fund of the National Sharecroppers Fund, Incorporated, New York. (Box 146)
    - Russia - Politics and Government, n.p. (Box 146)
    - Russian Economic Institute. New York, New York. (Box 146)
    - Russian Information Bureau in the U.S. New York, New York. (Box 146)
    - Russian Soviet Government Bureau. New York, New York. (Box 146)
    - Russian War Relief Incorporated, n.p. (Box 146)
  - S
    - Sacco-Vanzetti Defense Committee. Boston, Massachusetts. (Box 146)
    - Salazar Tribune. Pico Rivera, California. (Box 147)
      Note: January 9, 1971.
    - San Diego Patriotic Society, n.p. (Box 147)
    - San Fernando Committee of Concern. Van Nuys, California. (Box 147)
    - San Gabriel Valley Emergency Council on the Crisis in American Foreign Policy. Alhambra, California. (Box 147)
    - Sanity Publishing Cooperative. Montreal, Canada. (Box 147)
    - Santa Monicans for Renters' Rights. Santa Monica, California. (Box 147)
    - Save Medi-Cal Campaign. Los Angeles, California. (Box 147)
    - Schmitz Newsletter. Corona Del Mar, California. (Box 147)
    - Schneiderman - Darcy Defense Committee. San Francisco, California. (Box 147)
    - Scholarship, Education and Defense Fund for Racial Equality, Incorporated, New York. (Box 147)
    - Science & Education. Los Angeles, California. (Box 147)
    - Scottsboro Defense Committee. New York, New York. (Box 147)
    - Screen Writers' Guild, n.p. (Box 147)
    - Sea and Colonial League of Poland, Warsaw. (Box 147)
    - Searchlight Publishing Company. Washington, D.C. (Box 147)
    - Seattle Group. Seattle, Washington. (Box 147)
    - Seattle Peace Information Center. Seattle, Washington. (Box 147)
    - Second Amendment Foundation. Bellevue, Washington. (Box 147)
    - Selective Service System, n.p. (Box 147)
    - Selma Federal Building Defendants. Los Angeles, California. (Box 147)
    - Sentinels of the Republic. Washington, D.C. (Box 147)
    - Serbia, n.p. (Box 147)
    - Seventh [7th] Step Foundation, n.p. (Box 147)
    - Sex Information and Education Council of the U.S. (SIECUS), New York. (Box 147)
    - Sheppard-Hill Bill, n.p. (Box 147)
    - Sierra Club, n.p. (Box 147)
    - Silver Shirts of America. Los Angeles, California. (Box 147)
    - Simon J. Lubin Society of California, Incorporated. San Francisco, California. (Box 147)
    - Slam, Chino, California. (Box 147)
    - Smith, Billy Dean, n.p. (Box 147)
    - Smith, Gerald Lyman Kenneth, 1898-, n.p. (Box 147)
      Note: Includes The New Letters, pamphlets, printed ephemera, 1945 -
    - Social Action. New York, New York. (Box 147)
    - Social Action Communicator. Pacoima, California. (Box 147)
    - Social Concerns Action Committee. Los Angeles, California. (Box 147)
    - Social Democratic Federation of America. New York, New York. (Box 147)
    - Social Economic Foundation, Incorporated. New York, New York. (Box 148)
    - Social Medicine, n.p. (Box 148)
    - Social Workers' Emergency Committee, n.p. (Box 148)
    - Socialism, n.p. (Box 148)
    - Socialism - U.S., n.p. (Box 148)
    - Socialism In Australia, n.p. (Box 148)
    - Socialism In Canada, n.p. (Box 148)
    - Socialism In Great Britain, n.p. (Box 149, Box 150)
    - Socialism In Mexico, n.p. (Box 148)